Guide to the Sidney D. Gamble photographs, 1906-2007 RL.10074
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Sidney D. Gamble Foundation Records, 1919-2006, 5 boxes
  - Life in China around the May 4th Movement, an exhibition at the Hong Kong Heritage Museum, 2001-2004, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - List of exhibitions in the United States and China, 1991; 2006-2007 (Box 11)
  - List of people invited to China exhibitions, 1999 and undated (Box 11)
  - Magazine and newspaper articles about China Between Revolutions exhibition, 1988-2000 and undated (Box 12)
  - Material related to ISBN application for exhibition catalog, 1989 (Box 12)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1970-2000 and undated (Box 12)
  - Miscellaneous mail, 2001 (Box 12)
  - Miscellaneous materials about China, 1986-1995 and undated (Box 12)
  - Museum bookings and letters to museums about exhibition, 1989-1990 (Box 12)
  - Photographs from exhibition in Hefei, Anhui Province, 2006 (Box 12)
  - Photographs of exhibitions at unidentified locations (Box 12)
  - Photographs, Following Gamble's Footsteps, 2006 (Box 12)
  - Photographs from exhibition at Fujian Museum, 2006 (Box 12)
  - Photographs from exhibition at Shanxi Art Museum, 2006 and undated (Box 12)
  - Photographs from exhibition at Shaoxing Museum, 2006 (Box 12)
  - Photographs from exhibition at Hohhut, Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region, 2006 (Box 12)
  - Proposals and letters from Wayne Xing regarding an exhibition in China, 1993-1997 and undated (Box 12)
  - List of photographs sent to China for exhibition, 1997 and undated (Box 12)
  - Public relations information for exhibitions in China from Paula Webster Public Relations, 1999 (Box 12)
  - Requests for books and permission to use Sidney D. Gamble photographs, 1995-2007 and undated, 3 folders (Box 12)
  - Turbulent Years: Sidney D. Gamble's Photographs of China, an exhibition (Box 13)
    - Chengdu, 2000 (Box 13)
    - Chongquing, 2000 (Box 13)
    - Guangzhou, 2000 (Box 13)
    - Hangzhou, 2000 (Box 13)
    - Jinan, 1989-2000 (Box 13)
    - Jinhua, 2000 (Box 13)
    - Nanjing, 2000 (Box 13)
    - Shanghai, 1996-1997 and undated (Box 13)
    - Shenzhen, 2000 (Box 13)
    - Shijiazhuang, 2000 (Box 13)
    - Tianjin, 2001 (Box 13)
    - Zhengzhou, 2000 (Box 13)
  - W. W. Norton and Company: Correspondence and catalogs, 1989-1991, 1998 (Box 13)
  - Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA): Photocopies of annual report, 1919; and correspondence, 1925-1926, 1931 (Box 13)
- Photographic Material Series, 1906-1992, 24 boxes
  Photographic materials in the collection chiefly consist of several formats of the approximately 5,000 images that Gamble captured during his four sojourns in China (1908, 1917-1919, 1924-1927, and 1931-1932) and visits to other locales including Korea, Japan, Russia, Hawaii, and San Francisco. The images document urban and rural life, public events, architecture, religious statuary, and the countryside. Gamble used the images to illustrate scholarly publications and in slide lectures. Formats include contact sheets, hand-colored glass slides, duplicate slides (35mm), copy prints, a photograph album (120 contact prints), and nitrate negatives. Also included are print and card indexes to the photographs, and the original negative sleeves (with annotations).
  - Card Index to Photographs
    The card index provides access to images by location, name, and subject.
    - Card index (Box 14)
  - Contact Sheets, 1917-1932
    Contact sheets were created by the donor in the 1980s from the original nitrate negatives to serve as a reference tool for the collection. There are typically six images per contact sheet with brief descriptions of each image including the location and subject matter.
    Contact sheets are arranged by roll and exposure number
    - Photograph/slide subject index, undated (Box 15)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (1A/1-3A/17) (Box 15)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (4A/18-8A/41) (Box 15)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (8A/42-13A/62) (Box 15)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (13A/63-17A/84) (Box 15)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (17A/85-20A/103) (Box 15)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (20A/104-23A/121) (Box 15)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (23A/122-26A/141) (Box 15)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (27A/142-30A/161) (Box 15)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (30A/162-33A/179) (Box 15)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (33A/180-37A/199) (Box 15)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (37A/200-41A/220) (Box 15)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (41A/221-44A/242) (Box 15)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (45A/243-47A/261) (Box 15)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (48A/262-51A/278) (Box 15)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (51A/279-54A/294) (Box 15)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (55A/295-58A/314) (Box 15)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (58A/315-61A/334) (Box 15)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (61A/335-65A/354) (Box 15)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (65A/355-68A/375) (Box 15)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (69A/376-72A/395) (Box 15)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (72A/396-75A/416) (Box 15)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (75A/417-78A/436) (Box 15)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (79A/437-82A/456) (Box 15)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (82A/457-85A/476) (Box 15)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (85A/477-89A/496) (Box 15)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (89A/477-92A/515) (Box 15)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (92A/516-96/535) (Box 15)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 ( 96/536-99/555) (Box 15)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 ( 99/556-102/574) (Box 15)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 ( 103/575-106/595) (Box 15)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 ( 106/594-110/614) (Box 15)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 ( 110/615-112/631) (Box 15)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 ( 112/632-116/651) (Box 15)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 ( 116/652-118/667) (Box 15)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 ( 118/667A-121/684) (Box 15)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 ( 122/686-125/706) (Box 15)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 ( 126/707-129/726) (Box 15)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 ( 129/727-132/745) (Box 15)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (65A/355-68A/375) (Box 15)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 ( 137/746-136/765) (Box 16)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (136/766-139/782) (Box 16)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (139-783-142/801) (Box 16)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (142/802-145/816) (Box 16)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (145/817-148/832) (Box 16)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (151/850-155/866) (Box 16)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (155/867-158/886) (Box 16)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (158/887-162/905) (Box 16)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (162/905B-164/922) (Box 16)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (168/942-171/961) (Box 16)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (171/962-174/980) (Box 16)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (175/981-178/1000) (Box 16)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (178/1001-182/1919A) (Box 16)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (182/1020-185/1037) (Box 16)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (185/1038-189/1056) (Box 16)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (189/1057-192/1075) (Box 16)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 ( 193/1076-195/1092) (Box 16)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (195/1093-196/1098) (Box 16)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (196/1097-199/1116) (Box 16)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (200/1117-203/1143) (Box 16)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (203/1135-206/1153) (Box 16)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (207/1154-210/1171) (Box 16)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 ( 211/1172-214/1195) (Box 16)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (214/1196-218/1215) (Box 16)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (218/1216-221/1235) (Box 16)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (221/1236-224/1255) (Box 16)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (225/1256-228/1278) (Box 16)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (228/1279-232/1301) (Box 16)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (231/1295-235/1318) (Box 16)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (235/1319-237/1330) (Box 16)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (237/1331-240/1349) (Box 16)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (240/1350-243/1366) (Box 16)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (243/1367-246/1383) (Box 16)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (247/1387-250/1409) (Box 16)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (250/1406-253/1425) (Box 17)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (253/1426-254/1444) (Box 17)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (254/1445-256/1461) (Box 17)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (256/1462-259/1479) (Box 17)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (260/1484-263/1501) (Box 17)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (263/1502-266/1519) (Box 17)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (266/1520-269/1539) (Box 17)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (269/1540-272/1557) (Box 17)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (273/1561-275/1576) (Box 17)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (276/1577-279/1595) (Box 17)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (279/1596-281/1612) (Box 17)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (282/1613-284/1628) (Box 17)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (285/1629-287/1646) (Box 17)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (287/1646-290/1662) (Box 17)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (291/1663-294/1681) (Box 17)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (294/1682-298/1704) (Box 17)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (298/1705-301/1722) (Box 17)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (301/1723-305/1747) (Box 17)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (305/1748-308/1763) (Box 17)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (308/1746-312/1783) (Box 17)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (312/1784-313/1794) (Box 17)
    - Sojourn, 1919, 1924 (314/1795-312/1816) (Box 17)
    - Sojourn, 1919, 1924 (317/1817-321/1840) (Box 17)
    - Sojourn, 1919, 1924 (322/1841-326/1864) (Box 17)
    - Sojourn, 1919, 1924 (326/1865-330/1890) (Box 17)
    - Sojourn, 1919, 1924 (351/2001-354/2022) (Box 17)
    - Sojourn, 1919, 1924 (354/2023-359/2053) (Box 17)
    - Sojourn, 1919, 1924 (360/2056-363/2078) (Box 17)
    - Sojourn, 1919, 1924 (364/2083-369/2111) (Box 17)
    - Sojourn, 1919, 1924 (369/2112-373/2137) (Box 17)
    - Sojourn, 1919, 1924 (373/2138-377/2161) (Box 17)
    - Sojourn, 1919, 1924 (377/2162-383/2193) (Box 18)
    - Sojourn, 1919, 1924 (383/2194-389/2231) (Box 18)
    - Sojourn, 1919, 1924 (389/2232-395/2265) (Box 18)
    - Sojourn, 1919, 1924 (395/2266-400/2299) (Box 18)
    - Sojourn, 1924-1925 (400/2300-408/2344) (Box 18)
    - Sojourn, 1924-1925 (408/2345-415/2385) (Box 18)
    - Sojourn, 1924-1925 (415/2386-422/2426) (Box 18)
    - Sojourn, 1924-1925 (422/2427-429/2471) (Box 18)
    - Sojourn, 1924-1925 (430/2472-438/2518) (Box 18)
    - Sojourn, 1924-1925 (438/2519-445/2562) (Box 18)
    - Sojourn, 1924-1925 (445/2563-452/2600) (Box 18)
    - Sojourn, 1924-1925 (452/2601-459/2644) (Box 18)
    - Sojourn, 1924-1925 (459/2645-463/2671) (Box 18)
    - Sojourn, 1924-1925 (464/2672-468/2698) (Box 18)
    - Sojourn, 1925 (468/2699-274/2733) (Box 18)
    - Sojourn, 1925 (474/2734-481/2771) (Box 18)
    - Sojourn, 1925 (481/2771-487/2808) (Box 18)
    - Sojourn, 1925 (487/2809-492/2841) (Box 18)
    - Sojourn, 1925 (493/2842-497/2867) (Box 18)
    - Sojourn, 1925 (497/2868-502/2898) (Box 18)
    - Sojourn, 1925 (502/2899-508/2935) (Box 18)
    - Sojourn, 1925 (508/2936-514/2975) (Box 19)
    - Sojourn, 1925 (515/2976-520/3012) (Box 19)
    - Sojourn, 1925 (521/3013-523/3030) (Box 19)
    - Sojourn, 1925 (524/3032-530/3068) (Box 19)
    - Sojourn, 1925 (530/3069-535/3100) (Box 19)
    - Sojourn, 1925-1926 (536/3101-542/3140) (Box 19)
    - Sojourn, 1925-1926 (542/3141-549/3130) (Box 19)
    - Sojourn, 1925-1926 (549/3181-555/3217) (Box 19)
    - Sojourn, 1925-1926 (557/3226-563/3266) (Box 19)
    - Sojourn, 1925-1926 (563/3266-571/3311) (Box 19)
    - Sojourn, 1925-1926 (572/3312-579/3358) (Box 19)
    - Sojourn, 1925-1926 (579/3359-586/3408) (Box 19)
    - Sojourn, 1925-1926 (586/3410-593/3458) (Box 19)
    - Sojourn, 1925-1926 (594/3459-599/3497) (Box 19)
    - Sojourn, 1927, 1931-1932 (615/3591-623/3636) (Box 19)
    - Sojourn, 1927, 1931-1932 (600/3498-607/3544) (Box 19)
    - Sojourn, 1927, 1931-1932 (607/3544-615/3588) (Box 19)
    - Sojourn, 1927, 1931-1932 (623/3637-630/3683) (Box 19)
    - Sojourn, 1927, 1931-1932 (630/3683-638/3729) (Box 19)
    - Sojourn, 1927, 1931-1932 (638/3730-646/3776) (Box 20)
    - Sojourn, 1927, 1931-1932 (646/3777-653/3819) (Box 20)
    - Sojourn, 1927, 1931-1932 (654/3840-663/3825) (Box 20)
    - B-Film, 1917-1927 (1B/1-8B/66) (Box 20)
    - B-Film, 1917-1927 (8B/67-14B/131) (Box 20)
    - B-Film, 1917-1927 (14B/132-20B/197) (Box 20)
    - B-Film, 1917-1927 (20B/198-26B/269) (Box 20)
    - B-Film, 1917-1927 (26B/266-32B/333) (Box 20)
    - B-Film, 1917-1927 (32B/334-39B/405) (Box 20)
    - B-Film, 1917-1927 (39B/406-45B/475) (Box 20)
    - B-Film, 1917-1927 (45B/476-51B/545) (Box 20)
    - B-Film, 1917-1927 (51B/546-57B/616) (Box 20)
    - B-Film, 1917-1927 (51B/617-63B/676) (Box 20)
    - B-Film, 1917-1927 (63B/677-69B/747) (Box 20)
    - B-Film, 1917-1927 (69B/748-74B/799) (Box 20)
    - B-Film, 1917-1927 (74B/800-77B/843) (Box 20)
  - Duplicate Prints, 1917-1932
    Large (8x10) and small (2x4) photographic prints made for various publications and exhibitions of Gamble's work.
    - Contact Print Extras (Box 20)
    - Color Transparencies (Box 20)
    - Duplicate Prints (Large) (Box 21)
    - Select Duplicate Prints (Large and Small) (Box 21)
    - Duplicate prints and photocopies (Box 21)
    - Computerized prints (Box 21)
    - Duplicate prints (Box 22)
  - Duplicate Slides (35mm), 1917-1932
    Multiple sets of approximately 500 35mm duplicate slides. Each set consists of 13 small individually labeled slide cases. The 35mm slides are duplicates of selected hand-colored glass slides and black and white negatives in the collection. Also included are three small slide cases labeled test extras, containing slides of artwork and other scenes unrelated to the bulk of the collection.
    Duplicate slides are arranged numerically by exposure number. Labels on each case note the exposures in that case. Sets are distinguished by a colored dot marked on each box in that set.
    - Duplicate slides (35mm) (Box 23-24)
  - Exhibit Catalogs
    - China Between Revolutions (1989-1993) (Box 25)
    - Turbulent Years: China Before and After the May 4th Movement (1999) (Box 25)
    - Sidney Gamble's China Revisited (2004) (Box 25)
  - Glass Slides, 1906-1927
    - Glass slides: China, 1908-1927 (Box 26-34)
      Approximately 600 glass slides, mostly depicting Gamble's travels in China. The bulk of the slides are hand-colored versions of black-and-white images found elsewhere in the collection, but there are also slides featuring charts and graphs that Gamble used in his lectures and presentations on China.
      The original order of the hand-colored glass slides has been preserved. These slides were loosely arranged in alphabetical order by topic. Some slides are labeled with an exposure number and a brief description of the subject matter, while other slides contain no identifiers.
    - Glass slides: Western United States, circa 1906 (Box 35)
      Approximately 50 glass slides belonging to David Gamble, mostly depicting landscapes and other scenes in the Western United States such as: Old Faithful Geyser, the Grand Canyon, bears, and waterfalls. Also included are portraits of unidentified women.
  - Microfilm
    Microfilm of the Sidney D. Gamble Photographs, 1911-1919, held at Princeton University.
    - Microfilm (Box 24)
  - Negative sleeves
    - Original negative sleeves (with annotations) (Box 36-37)
  - Photograph Album
    - Photograph album, circa 1908 (Box 38)
      Contains 120 prints, most likely taken during Gamble's 1908 sojourn to China.
  - Negatives, 1917-1932; 4 Linear Feet 13 boxes
    Conditions Governing Access
    Original nitrate negatives may not be viewed in the reading room. Digital surrogates are available for use. Please consult with Rubenstein staff.
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    These film negatives are composed of cellulose nitrate, which is very flammable and can present a health hazard.
    - Original Gamble negatives (nitrate) (Box 41-53)
      Original nitrate negatives are non-circulating and may not be viewed in the reading room. Digital surrogates are available for use. Please consult with Rubenstein staff.
- Printed Material Series, circa 1910s-1996
  Includes mandarin character drill cards and Mandarin Readers used in the North China Union Language School, and a 1996 senior thesis on the origins and evolution of the Princeton in Asia program.
  - Character drill cards, circa 1910s (Box 39)
  - Mandarin Readers, undated, 5 envelopes (Box 39)
  - Men of Faith, Men of Action: The Origins and Evolution of the Princeton in Asia Program, 1898-1937. (Box 39)
    A senior thesis by Andrea Yun-Woei Au, Department of History, Princeton University, 1996.
  - Card index to Sidney Gamble's private library. (Box 39)
- Oversize Material, 1924-2007, 1 boxes
  - Preservation photocopies of Scrapbook, 1924-1929 (Box 40)
  - Articles related to China, Asia, or photography, 1982-1986 (Box 40)
  - Chinese aphorisms with English translations, undated (Box 40)
  - Information and map about educational sessions in Ding county, undated (Box 40)
  - Special editions of newspaper Peking Ching Pao, focusing on Miao Feng Shan, 1925 May 13, 23, and 29 (Box 40)
  - Year of the Photograph: Gamble on China; Delano's Bittersweet Harvest, Siteline, Winter 1990 (Box 40)
  - Clippings, Shenzhen Evening News, Shenzhen Daily, and Guangzhou Morning Post, 2000 August and undated (Box 40)
  - Windows on the Many Chinese Revolutions, Political and Personal, The New York Times, 2004 July 2 (Box 40)
  - Exhibition poster from the University of Cincinnati's Tangeman Fine Arts Gallery, 1990 September 18 (Box 40)
  - Magazine and newspaper articles about China Between Revolutions exhibition, 1986-1995, 2 folders (Box 40)
  - Newspaper articles related to Life in China around the May Fourth Movement, an exhibition at the Hong Kong Heritage Museum, 2003 (Box 40)
  - Newspaper publicity related to exhibition at Changsha Museum in China, 2007 March (Box 40)
  - Poster, 1997 (Oversize-folder 1)